<?xml version='1.0'?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
]>

<chapter id="The_Open_Source_Way-What_Red_Hat_does_wrong_so_lets_stop">
  <title>What Red Hat does wrong, so let's stop</title>
  <section id="The_Open_Source_Way-What_Red_Hat_does_wrong_so_lets_stop-Burns_projects_and_losses_momentum_in_technology_leadership_by_ignoring_community_fundamentals">
    <title>Burns projects and losses momentum in technology leadership
    by ignoring community fundamentals</title>
    <!-- Principle -->
    <para>Ironically, Red Hat is not always the best at what it does.
    Sometimes we break every rule in <citetitle>The Open Source Way</citetitle>.
    </para>
    <!-- Implementation -->
    <para>
      <replaceable>Implementation needed</replaceable>
    </para>
    <!-- Example -->
    <para>
      <replaceable>Example needed</replaceable>
    </para>
  </section>
  <section id="The_Open_Source_Way-What_Red_Hat_does_wrong_so_lets_stop-Breaks_fundamental_rules_of_community">
    <title>Breaks fundamental rules of community</title>
    <!-- Principle -->
    <para>
      In fact, every rule is being broken right now, somewhere inside
      of Red Hat.
    </para>
    <!-- Implementation -->
    <para>
      Somewhere project team members are designing in the hallway
      instead of on a mailing list.
    </para>
    <!-- Example -->
    <para>
      For example, there is a long practice of having two mailing
      lists for open projects.  One is an internal list that too often
      gets used for development discussions before bringing them in
      to the open.  The other is the public discussion and
      development list.
    </para>
    <para>
      The problem is, community members either know or can feel there
      is work happening before conversations get to the public list.
    </para>
  </section>
  <section id="The_Open_Source_Way-What_Red_Hat_does_wrong_so_lets_stop-Fails_to_learn_from_mistakes">
    <title>Fails to learn from mistakes</title>
    <!-- Principle -->
    <para>
      Our ability to institutionally learn from past mistakes is hobbled.
    </para>
    <para>
      <citetitle>The Open Source Way</citetitle> is one part of fixing
      this.
    </para>
    <para>
      As with many of these "does it right, does it wrong" items,
      there is an irony at work here.  In many ways, Red Hat has
      learned serious lessons from past mistakes.  Yet still, we see
      many of the same ones repeated continuously.
    </para>
    <!-- Implementation -->
    <para>
      <replaceable>Implementation needed</replaceable>
    </para>
    <!-- Example -->
    <para>
      <replaceable>Example needed</replaceable>
    </para>
  </section>
  <section id="The_Open_Source_Way-What_Red_Hat_does_wrong_so_lets_stop-Misses_the_opportunity_to_adopt_and_grow_key_or_future_open_source_technology_for_our_own_IT">
      <title>Misses the opportunity to adopt and grow key or future open source technology for our own IT</title>
      <!-- Principle -->
      <para>
	Red Hat history is riddled with decisions to use a piece of
	proprietary technology for internal or external purposes.  In
	some cases there was no open source choice to adopt and the
	cost of starting from the beginning was prohibitive.
      </para>
<!-- Implementation-->
      <para>
	There are, however, as many cases where the open source
	software could have been adopted and fixed up to the needed
	enterprise standard by ''using the open source methodology.''
      </para>
      <!-- Example -->
      <para>
	<replaceable>Example needed</replaceable>
      </para>
  </section>      
  <section id="The_Open_Source_Way-What_Red_Hat_does_wrong_so_lets_stop-Does_not_include_community_strategy_in_all_new_projects">
    <title>Does not include community strategy in all new projects</title>
    <!-- Principle -->
    <para>
      Even a project that is only for internal focus and consumption
      can benefit from considering and including its community.
    </para>
    <!-- Implementation -->
    <para>
      In other words, we can adopt open source methodologies for
      everything from our internal communication to brand marketing.
    </para>
    <!-- Example -->
    <para>
      At the Google headquarters, there are brief articles posted on
      the bathroom walls, along with encouraging signs.  The articles
      are short and technical, detailing how to use and test a
      particular piece of Google technology.  The other signs and
      branding encourage Googlers to beta test their own software.
      This is sometimes called <firstterm><ulink
      url="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Eat_one%27s_own_dog_food">eating
      your own dog food</ulink></firstterm>, that is, using the
      products and methods yourself that you sell and encourage your
      customer communities to use.
    </para>
  </section>
  <section id="The_Open_Source_Way-What_Red_Hat_does_wrong_so_lets_stop-Separates_community_from_business">
    <title>Separates community from business</title>
    <!-- Principle -->
    <para>
      Unlike many other companies, Red Hat currently distinguishes
      clearly between the worlds of "development" (.org: as in JBoss
      and Fedora) where we support and work with communities, and
      "business", where we prefer hierarchical controlled structures.
    </para>
    <!-- Implementation -->
    <para>
      The separation becomes clear from our web pages, where <ulink
      url="http://www.redhat.com/"/> shows an unexplained link to
      "Fedora". Or on <ulink url="http://www.jboss.com/"/>, where the
      separation is emphasized by a <ulink
      url="http://www.jboss.com/products/community-enterprise/">transition
      page</ulink>.
    </para>
    <para>
      From Red Hat's historical evolution, this separation is
      comprehensible.
    </para>
    <para>
      Unfortunately, we can't always explain this history so it makes
      sense in the modern context where open community organizations
      act in a more integrated manner.
    </para>
    <para>
      A key community growth initiative that will benefit the Red Hat
      bottom line is to make growing various types of communities
      (customers, sales, partners, etc.) a top-level strategic goal.
      Agree that we need to include community interaction as part of
      the feedback loop that improves our business and processes.
    </para>
    <!-- Example -->
    <para>
      There are examples out there, where companies successfully
      integrate community principles into their business and gain
      benefits from customer and partner contributions as Red Hat does
      from development.
    </para>
    <para>
      A good exercise is the comparison of community integration on
      the web sites between <ulink url="http://www.redhat.com"/> and
      <ulink url="http://www.jboss.com JBoss"/> on one hand and <ulink
      url="http://www.oracle.com Oracle"/>, <ulink
      url="http://www.sap.com SAP"/>, <ulink
      url="http://www.novell.com Novell"/>, and <ulink
      url="http://www.ibm.com IBM"/> on the other hand.  A similar
      exercise can be done with smaller pure and mixed open source
      ISVs.  The community is forefront and listening to/interacting
      with users is a key to their growth.
    </para>
  </section>
</chapter>
